<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Chris Hoffman</title>
    <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Chris Hoffman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 20:55:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://hoffmanc.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unbuffered</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/unbuffered/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 20:55:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/unbuffered/</guid>
      <description>TIL that python STDOUT is buffered by default (at least for python3). You can get docker logs output by passing the -u flag. I added this to my shebang, so I only have to do ./main.py to run my script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSL</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 17:13:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/ssl/</guid>
      <description>Some notes so maybe I don&amp;rsquo;t forget how SSL certs work again:
 certificates are arranged in a chain from CA down the CA cert is special only because it is at the top of the chain you need to use the higher level cert to create lower level ones if you want them in the chain if you don&amp;rsquo;t need a separate authority, you can just use a self signed cert as the trusted root certificate (synonymous with CA?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K8s Port Forwarding</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/k8s-port-forwarding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 13:36:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/k8s-port-forwarding/</guid>
      <description>I have redis in a pod, and wanted to connect to it to see some usage stats this morning.
My initial, naive attempt was to hit redis directly, thinking maybe the k8s master maps these internal hostnames out to the host; no bueno.
Next I tried connecting to the pod directly via kubectl exec -it pod/redis-123812739 sh but once I get in there I cannot telnet because that isn&amp;rsquo;t installed. I could&amp;rsquo;ve installed telnet, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to add custom stuff to a k8s-managed container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replication</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/replication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:56:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/replication/</guid>
      <description>I spent the last couple of days figuring out if I can replicate a master server to a standby (formerly slave) server, without directly connecting to the master from the standby. The master servers are on premise in this case, and behind a VPN. We need to be able to query this standby, and collect records</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>assert.Len</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/assert.len/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 22:21:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/assert.len/</guid>
      <description>TIL that you can replace
assert.Equal(t, 3, len(someSlice)) with
assert.Len(t, someSlice, 3) Why they mix up which is the expected param is beyond me, but otherwise I like not having to add the len().</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Equal Values</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/equal-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 18:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/equal-values/</guid>
      <description>TIL that assert.EqualValues allows one to compare numerals of differing types for equality:
package main import ( &amp;#34;testing&amp;#34; &amp;#34;github.com/stretchr/testify/assert&amp;#34; ) func TestFoo(t *testing.T) { assert.EqualValues(t, int64(1), uint(1)) assert.EqualValues(t, int64(1), 1.0) } These asserts should both pass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/streaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:50:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/streaming/</guid>
      <description>I often get down on how verbose Go is as compared to Ruby. However, this is an example where Go (and go-gin) is quite terse for what it&amp;rsquo;s doing:
chanStream := make(chan string) go func() { defer close(chanStream) for i := 0; i &amp;lt; 10; i += 1 { chanStream &amp;lt;- fmt.Sprintf(&amp;#34;msg %d&amp;#34;, i) } }() c.Stream(func(w io.Writer) bool { if msg, ok := &amp;lt;-chanStream; ok { c.SSEvent(&amp;#34;message&amp;#34;, msg) return true } return false }) In this code we create a streaming HTTP response, such that the main server is not tied up while sending down data to the client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Compose Override</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/docker-compose-override/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 16:56:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/docker-compose-override/</guid>
      <description>Note to self: if I am not seeing env var overrides that I specify in a docker compose override file, check the following:
 is the file spelled correctly (e.g., hyphens vs periods and singular!) docker-compose.override.yml is it in the same directory as docker-compose.yml? is the dk convenience alias/script directly citing the config files, such as docker-compose -f docker-compose.yml? If so, you need to add another -f with the override.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Timestamps</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/git-timestamps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 16:38:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/git-timestamps/</guid>
      <description>I just ran into a scenario where the git log was not telling me the correct order of commits. This mis-ordering happened because git only keeps/considers the commit timestamps up to the nearest second. So, if you have a script that is creating a bunch of commits, you could have several that are associated with one second, which will result in the mis-ordering.
To get a more accurate order, use the --graph option on git log.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>k8s Monitoring</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/k8s-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 23:57:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/k8s-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>Some commands that are useful for monitoring k8s:
&amp;gt; kubectl get namespace NAME STATUS AGE c66-system Active 83d default Active 83d kube-node-lease Active 83d kube-public Active 83d kube-system Active 83d menopon Active 83d &amp;gt; kubectl get pods --namespace=menopon NAME READY STATUS RESTARTS AGE redis-649f7db499-sl6h4 1/1 Running 0 74d web-69c576797d-7x7h2 1/1 Running 0 74d web-69c576797d-mjgfs 1/1 Running 0 74d web-69c576797d-zbfkz 1/1 Running 0 74d also, look to /var/log/pods for pod logs:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mui Class Override</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/mui-class-override/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 22:43:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/mui-class-override/</guid>
      <description>If you need to override some CSS in a component that you didn&amp;rsquo;t author, but aren&amp;rsquo;t sure what the options are, just use a dummy one and check the dev tools console for errors. The available class names should be listed in the error message.
const classes = useStyles() &amp;lt;ExternalComponent classes={{dummy: classes.myCssClass}}/&amp;gt; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>try/finally in Bash</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/tryfinallybash/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 22:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/tryfinallybash/</guid>
      <description>If you need to do some cleanup whether or not a part of a bash script ran successfully, but also want to exit immediately if other stuff in that script fails, use a subshell:
set -e # exit immediately on error touch fileThatAlwaysGetsRemoved # if this fails it exits without the cleanup ( # &amp;lt;--- subshell set -e executableThatLooksForTheFileAndMaybeFails ) rm fileThatAlwaysGetsRemoved </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Compose Env Vars</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/docker-compose-env-vars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 21:42:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/docker-compose-env-vars/</guid>
      <description>TIL that docker compose knows when environment variables have changed, and intelligently recreates containers on up if so. Also, environment variables do not get updated to what&amp;rsquo;s in the .env file on a restart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pi4midi</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/pi4midi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 15:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/pi4midi/</guid>
      <description>I promised my daughter Lila that I&amp;rsquo;d get this USB-MIDI keyboard controller working, which I had been talking about doing for some weeks, but which has become more pertinent, given that we are going to be homeschooling, and music is part of our curriculum.
Anyway, here are notes on how I got MIDI sound working on a Pi4 2GB with my Nektar IMPACT iX61 MIDI controller:
Setup  Install base raspberry OS apt install qsynth Start jackd with the seq module so the MIDI keyboard works (from http://slackermedia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thermostat</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/thermostat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 13:48:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/thermostat/</guid>
      <description>Notes for how I go about setting up my Pi-Zero-W-based thermostat, since I keep having to reflash the SD card due to a poor power supply (I know, the right one is cheap&amp;hellip; yes yes).
 Get Pi latest Raspberry Pi OS Lite Change passwd Go into sudo raspi-config  change hostname to thermostat enable wifi enable SSH   reboot ssh-keygen add pub key to github git clone git@github.com:hoffmanc/heater.git cd heater sudo .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brightness</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/brightness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:42:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/brightness/</guid>
      <description>I tried to help a colleague to get their brightness hotkeys working on Ubuntu using the i3wm. I had googled and implemented a solution for it, but then forgot what I did. So, here it is, for the sake of Future Chris. This solution is applicable to the lenovo t470p and t480 at least.
place this script in /etc/acpi/brightness.sh:
#!/bin/bash  current_brightness=`cat /sys/class/backlight/intel_backlight/brightness` max_brightness=`cat /sys/class/backlight/intel_backlight/max_brightness` if [ $1 == &amp;#34;up&amp;#34; ] then new_brightness=$(($current_brightness + 100)) [ $new_brightness -gt $max_brightness ] &amp;amp;&amp;amp; new_brightness=$max_brightness else new_brightness=$(($current_brightness - 100)) [ $new_brightness -lt 0 ] &amp;amp;&amp;amp; new_brightness=0 fi echo $new_brightness &amp;gt; /sys/class/backlight/intel_backlight/brightness and these under /etc/acpi/events:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Splice</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/splice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 13:02:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/splice/</guid>
      <description>A couple of days ago I learned about the javascript method splice for arrays, which allows one to delete and replace elements of an array in one call. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the immutable.js implementation of this method, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been quite pleased with how easy it is to e.g., move an element.
For example, given this List:
const ary = List([&amp;#39;a&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;b&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;c&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;d&amp;#39;]) If I want to move &amp;lsquo;b&amp;rsquo; to in between &amp;lsquo;c&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;d&amp;rsquo;, I would do the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ignore Revs</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/ignore-revs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 13:29:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/ignore-revs/</guid>
      <description>TIL that git version 2.23+ allows one to specify commits to ignore during a git blame. This is useful when there are commits that touched a lot of stuff but only changed formatting.
I was able to update my version of git on ubuntu by adding the git core ppa, apt updating and installing.
sudo add-apt-repository ppa:git-core/ppa Since I use tpope&amp;rsquo;s vim-fugitive to do blaming, I wanted not to have to specify the --ignore-rev flag every time I use this command, so I did the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amps</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/amps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 13:30:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/amps/</guid>
      <description>Today I learned that the little DC adapter I was trying to use to power a ODROID C1 was insufficient, at least when it came to spinning up a GUI.
I have this old Lenovo power adapter that is pushing 20V, so I&amp;rsquo;m looking into stepping down that voltage somehow to 5V. I tried to use a potentiometer to achieve this purpose, which likely belies my electronics knowledge - in short, it didn&amp;rsquo;t work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturn</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/saturn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 02:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/saturn/</guid>
      <description>Today Lila and I saw Saturn through her telescope! We could clearly make out it&amp;rsquo;s four moons and rings! I think this is the first time either of us have seen something so cool in a telescope (her being nine, so less unusual).
Now I feel compelled to learn some amateur astronomy.
And build a rocket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Front Matter</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/front-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 02:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/front-matter/</guid>
      <description>Today I learned how to add some tags to these articles, with the hope that I can use them to conditionally syndicate these posts to twitter, linkedin, etc.
I believe being able to generate an RSS feed for a script to use for syndication involves digging more deeply into taxonomies; specifically, making sure I am using a theme that supports rss templates for them, or adding my own?
UPDATE - after publishing this article, I see a syndications/twitter folder that has exactly what I need for a script to sync this blog with, in this case, twitter!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QRCode</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/qrcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 13:08:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/qrcode/</guid>
      <description>Chris, I am a QRCode. Remember my name, god damnit!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>useEffect style</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/use-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 02:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/use-effect/</guid>
      <description>I was able to modify the width of a stubborn react-admin component dynamically, using another DOM element as a reference point, and it was actually pretty clean! Here&amp;rsquo;s a stripped-down version:
MyComponent = () =&amp;gt; { [width, setWidth] = useState() useEffect(() =&amp;gt; { const main = document.querySelector(&amp;#39;main&amp;#39;); if (!main) { return; } setWidth(main.getBoundingClientRect().width - 50); }); render &amp;lt;StubbornComponent style={{width}}/&amp;gt; } I would&amp;rsquo;ve preferred a pure-CSS solution, but this seems to be working and the code is temporary (well, moreso than usual, hopefully)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gohang</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/gohang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 12:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/gohang/</guid>
      <description>To make a go program hang until terminated, you can use this line:
&amp;lt;-make(chan struct{}) Why would you want to do this? In our case we have a blue/green setup that and docker compose set to restart: always, so if the server reboots both the blue and green containers get spun up at the same time. Now we check to see which one is supposed to be active, and if a container doesn&amp;rsquo;t match, it executes this hang - otherwise docker will see the 0 exit code and constantly try restarting the container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>House</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/house/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 02:10:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/house/</guid>
      <description>This weekend I learned a bit about what goes into putting a house together. The biggest take away was that making sure all the pieces are square and level is critical, and saves a lot of time down the road.
For instance: there were two mud sills, or sill plates, on the foundation walls. The original plan was to shim the second course of sill so that it was totally level all the way around the foundation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unmarshal</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/unmarshal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:07:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/unmarshal/</guid>
      <description>Do not rely on the fact that go unmarshaled json without error into your type - it may just have ignored all the json and instantiated an empty variable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>git add `--edit`</title>
      <link>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/til/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 02:34:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hoffmanc.com/posts/til/</guid>
      <description>TIL that I can use git add --edit during an interactive rebase to do things like move a file from a go package (created in that commit) to an existing package; this reduces the scope of the regex substitution to avoid changing unrelated code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
